<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cyber on Navigating The Edge</title>
    <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/cyber/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cyber on Navigating The Edge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 08:02:45 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/cyber/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cyber 2012: Crossing the Threshold</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-01-cyber-2012-crossing-the-threshold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 08:02:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-01-cyber-2012-crossing-the-threshold/</guid>
      <description>The evolution of the cyber domain is as fascinating as it is concerning. It is a perfect example of the complexity we constuct in our modern world that provides significant asymmetries in favor of those who choose to attack the system. In 2012, we witnessed the continued evolution of collection and attack capabilities to unprecedented levels. I thought it would be worthwhile to review some highlights from the past year that in my mind only bolster the case for strengthening community resilience before high consequence events occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowdsourcing Cyberwar</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-08-crowdsourcing-cyberwar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 02:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-08-crowdsourcing-cyberwar/</guid>
      <description>On April 27, 2007, the Estonian government moved a controversial bronze statue of a Soviet soldier from its long-time resting place to a military graveyard outside the capital city of Tallinn. After 15 years of independence from the former Soviet Union, the government finally decided to take action to place this troubling symbol in a more remote location.  The reaction from the Russian minority was swift, with rioting and looting of downtown Tallinn that lasted for days.  Along with chaos in the streets came the beginning of a protracted cyberriot known now as the first Internet war.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
