<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Navigating The Edge</title>
    <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Navigating The Edge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 11:06:07 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-10-digital-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 11:06:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-10-digital-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>Do you trust your smartphone? Is there anything you would refrain from communicating or recording on your phone? If so, how do you decide where the threshold is? Each time we consider disclosing information online, we are faced with an ambiguous and dynamic tradeoff. One which we generally avoid even contemplating. And yet there are implications associated with the totality of our disclosure, especially when the Internet never forgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surveillance By Default</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-08-surveillance-by-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 10:11:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-08-surveillance-by-default/</guid>
      <description>In our hyperconnected world, does privacy even exist any longer? It’s hard to argue in the affirmative as networked devices permeate all aspects of our lives. What I find concerning is how we accept this condition. Many of the services we use are recording our digital lives en masse. Yet the details of these arrangements are constantly shifting as disclosures make clear. User privacy expectations are routinely violated and the cumulative implications of those violations are increasingly difficult to fathom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Relationships for Social Good</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-05-building-relationships-for-social-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 20:54:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-05-building-relationships-for-social-good/</guid>
      <description>For some time now, I&amp;rsquo;ve firmly believed that the novel opportunities for innovation lie at the boundaries between disciplines. My word choice in this statement belies the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent many years up until recently in the research world. As I reflect on this now, I prefer the more general statement we obtain when replacing &lt;em&gt;disciplines&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;communities&lt;/em&gt;. New opportunities become apparent when ideas and resources that are constrained in separate communities are allowed to mix. Often their mixture is the catalyst for new perspective and, in some cases, new steps forward.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
