<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crowdsourcing on Navigating The Edge</title>
    <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/crowdsourcing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crowdsourcing on Navigating The Edge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 16:03:15 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/crowdsourcing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Phone Entrepreneurship in the Developing World</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-09-mobile-phone-entrepreneurship-in-the-developing-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 16:03:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-09-mobile-phone-entrepreneurship-in-the-developing-world/</guid>
      <description>This morning, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about an exciting ongoing project called EPROM (Entrepreneurial Programming and Research on Mobiles) that is focused on fostering mobile-phone related research and entrepreneurship in the developing world. The EPROM project is lead by Nathan Eagle, whose seminal Ph.D. research at the MIT Media Laboratory focused on understanding complex human dynamics from social interaction data derived from mobile devices.
To fully appreciate the motivation for EPROM, it is important to consider the trends within Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowdsourcing Cyberwar</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-08-crowdsourcing-cyberwar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 02:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-08-crowdsourcing-cyberwar/</guid>
      <description>On April 27, 2007, the Estonian government moved a controversial bronze statue of a Soviet soldier from its long-time resting place to a military graveyard outside the capital city of Tallinn. After 15 years of independence from the former Soviet Union, the government finally decided to take action to place this troubling symbol in a more remote location.  The reaction from the Russian minority was swift, with rioting and looting of downtown Tallinn that lasted for days.  Along with chaos in the streets came the beginning of a protracted cyberriot known now as the first Internet war.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
