<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resilience on Navigating The Edge</title>
    <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/resilience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resilience on Navigating The Edge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 13:47:45 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/resilience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Illusions of Understanding and Control</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2015-12-illusions-understanding-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 13:47:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2015-12-illusions-understanding-control/</guid>
      <description>With the latest shooting in San Bernardino, it feels like our society is awakening to a new normal — one where the term &lt;em&gt;active shooter&lt;/em&gt; becomes common parlance in our everyday conversation. While the senseless deaths are tragic in their own right, it is similarly tragic to watch the paralyzing and polarizing effects of fear unfold in our society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framing Ambiguity, Incentives, and Actions</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2015-02-framing-ambiguity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 13:54:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2015-02-framing-ambiguity/</guid>
      <description>In the mid 90s, while working in government, I was given an invaluable bit of advice from an Air Force colonel who would become a trusted advisor and a dear friend. He said: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perspective is elusive&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with countless Ph.D.&amp;rsquo;s that would obsess over details which did not matter in the grand scheme of things. You seem to have the ability to operate on multiple levels. Don&amp;rsquo;t lose the ability to see the bigger picture.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Now - The Role of Data in Adaptive Organizations</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2014-06-understanding-the-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 14:32:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2014-06-understanding-the-now/</guid>
      <description>It was 2005. The war in Iraq was raging. Many of us in the national security R&amp;amp;D community were developing responses to the deadliest threat facing US soldiers: the improvised explosive device (IED). From the perspective of the US military, the unthinkable was happening each and every day. The world’s most technologically advanced military was being dealt significant blows by insurgents making crude weapons from limited resources. How was this even possible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illuminating the Social Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-07-illuminating-the-social-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 12:32:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-07-illuminating-the-social-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Recently I participated in &lt;em&gt;The City Resilient&lt;/em&gt;, an event organized by PopTech and the Rockefeller Foundation to bring together individuals with diverse backgrounds and experience that share a common interest in advancing the resilience of our communities. Day one of the event consisted of presentations from leading innovators and scholars working on advancing and understanding various aspects of resilience, from the personal to the ecological scale. Day two engaged a smaller group of attendees in a design exercise to generate new concepts that might serve as meaningful responses to the challenges we heard the day prior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grappling with Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-12-grappling-with-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 21:51:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-12-grappling-with-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to speak on several occasions with members of the national security community about organizational resilience in an uncertain world. These presentations have mainly been a continuation of musings that I began last year, leading me to write these two earlier posts on the subject. During these presentations, my aim has always been twofold: to make the audience more cognizant of the limits we face when attempting to reason about our world and to provide a general frame for thinking about operating in an environment that is fundamentally unpredictable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivating Challenges</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-11-motivating-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-11-motivating-challenges/</guid>
      <description>How might we inspire and enable communities to be inherently more resilient to global shocks and adaptive to changing realities?
Now, more than ever, it is imperative to search for viable answers to this question. In our globalized world, societies have become more fragile and vulnerable to cascading failures in networks. In domains such as cybersecurity, finance, energy production and distribution, the world continues to build systems whose complexities will never be fully understood.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
