<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Relationship Identification on Navigating The Edge</title>
    <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/social-relationship-identification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Relationship Identification on Navigating The Edge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 12:12:43 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/social-relationship-identification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Social Signaling and Language Use</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-04-social-signaling-and-language-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 12:12:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-04-social-signaling-and-language-use/</guid>
      <description>Consider the following email from Tim Belden to John Lavorato and Louise Kitchen. Recall that Tim Belden was indicted for his role in conceiving and executing various financial schemes that allowed Enron to profit significantly from energy markets. Through the analysis of the Enron email collection, we would like to understand who Belden was reporting to and who he was supervising during the time period of the California energy crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking Relationships, Discovering Evidence</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-01-ranking-relationships-discovering-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 13:53:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-01-ranking-relationships-discovering-evidence/</guid>
      <description>In my introductory post on the topic of social relationship identification (SRI), I talked about the need to develop a collaborative process where the machine guides the analyst in the discovery of relevant social relationships and learns from the context provided by the analyst. Both the analyst and the machine have important and complementary roles to play in the analytic process. The question is what specific form should that collaborative process take?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Relationship: Issues of Representation</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-the-social-relationship-issues-of-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 14:13:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-the-social-relationship-issues-of-representation/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, the domain of social network analysis (SNA) has become very popular among research communities outside the traditional SNA community in sociology. From the perspective of the sociologists, this has been a mixed blessing. The discipline of SNA, having a strong computational basis, stands to benefit from additional perspectives from other fields. Yet far too often, to the dismay of the sociologists, there is a lack of recognition of the importance of representational choices made prior to analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Relationship Identification: Defining the Task</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-sri-defining-the-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 13:51:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-sri-defining-the-task/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, informal, online communication has transformed the way we connect and collaborate with others. Through a range of online communication technologies, we are able to enrich existing social relationships and establish new relationships that would otherwise be difficult or impossible to develop offline. Now that storage has become vast and inexpensive, much of this data will be archived for years to come. This provides new opportunities and new challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
