<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Enterprise Analytics on Navigating The Edge</title>
    <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/enterprise-analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Enterprise Analytics on Navigating The Edge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 10:52:40 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/tags/enterprise-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Emergent Collaboration Through Community Sensemaking - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-12-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 10:52:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-12-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-4/</guid>
      <description>The challenge of uncovering substantive collaborations stems from the fact that we are searching for clustering across relationship structure, social context and time. As we discussed in the previous post, our representational choices constrain the types of questions we can answer. By constructing a global interaction network, aggregating interaction activity across all locations in a Jive community, we conflated interactions occurring across a number of social contexts. This eliminated our ability to uncover clusters of interaction activity occurring in a particular social context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Emergent Collaboration Through Community Sensemaking - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-10-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 13:28:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-10-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-3/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, we discussed the core problem of identifying groups of users engaged in substantive collaboration and began to formulate a solution based on interaction graph analysis. At the end of the post, we examined the first global interaction graph I rendered for a large multinational corporation. While it was exciting to see this global view for the first time, the global interaction graph provides negligible practical insight without additional processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Emergent Collaboration Through Community Sensemaking - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-09-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 15:51:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-09-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I introduced a central question organizations ask after the deployment of a new social collaboration platform: &lt;em&gt;What business value is the platform delivering for our organization?&lt;/em&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to reflect on factors that affect the resulting business value. Without question, general usability will have a significant impact. If the savviest users cannot accomplish their work in a more efficient manner, the platform has little hope of offering additional value. Users must ultimately discover how best to map their work into the platform to realize efficiency gains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Emergent Collaboration Through Community Sensemaking - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-09-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 08:31:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-09-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-1/</guid>
      <description>As social media transformed communication in our personal lives, it was not long before companies began positioning themselves to bring a similar transformation to the enterprise. Fostering adoption of enterprise social media has not been easy, especially given prevailing beliefs among many that social media provides little practical benefit. Questions continue to linger in the early stages of deployment as organizations seek to understand the platform&amp;rsquo;s value proposition for their operational context.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
