<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Navigating The Edge</title>
    <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Navigating The Edge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 22:18:44 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Manifestations of Fear</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2017-06-manifestations-of-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 22:18:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2017-06-manifestations-of-fear/</guid>
      <description>Late last year, I was driving south out of Tucson, Arizona to see a relic of the Cold War. Hidden in the stretches of the Sonoran desert is a small facility housing one of the most destructive creations of the US nuclear weapons program — the Titan II intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-10-digital-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 11:06:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-10-digital-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>Do you trust your smartphone? Is there anything you would refrain from communicating or recording on your phone? If so, how do you decide where the threshold is? Each time we consider disclosing information online, we are faced with an ambiguous and dynamic tradeoff. One which we generally avoid even contemplating. And yet there are implications associated with the totality of our disclosure, especially when the Internet never forgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surveillance By Default</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-08-surveillance-by-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 10:11:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-08-surveillance-by-default/</guid>
      <description>In our hyperconnected world, does privacy even exist any longer? It’s hard to argue in the affirmative as networked devices permeate all aspects of our lives. What I find concerning is how we accept this condition. Many of the services we use are recording our digital lives en masse. Yet the details of these arrangements are constantly shifting as disclosures make clear. User privacy expectations are routinely violated and the cumulative implications of those violations are increasingly difficult to fathom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future Perfect</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-06-future-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:26:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2016-06-future-perfect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;em&gt;“How can we accelerate our progress toward the singularity?”&lt;/em&gt; After hearing this opening question, I shifted in my seat and shot up my hand. I could barely contain myself. &lt;em&gt;“I want to object to the underlying premise of the question — that accelerating our progress toward the singularity is even desirable. Why do we want to endow machines with artificial general intelligence? To what end?”&lt;/em&gt; I scanned around the room, pausing for responses. None immediately came. I continued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Illusions of Understanding and Control</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2015-12-illusions-understanding-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 13:47:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2015-12-illusions-understanding-control/</guid>
      <description>With the latest shooting in San Bernardino, it feels like our society is awakening to a new normal — one where the term &lt;em&gt;active shooter&lt;/em&gt; becomes common parlance in our everyday conversation. While the senseless deaths are tragic in their own right, it is similarly tragic to watch the paralyzing and polarizing effects of fear unfold in our society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framing Ambiguity, Incentives, and Actions</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2015-02-framing-ambiguity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 13:54:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2015-02-framing-ambiguity/</guid>
      <description>In the mid 90s, while working in government, I was given an invaluable bit of advice from an Air Force colonel who would become a trusted advisor and a dear friend. He said: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perspective is elusive&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with countless Ph.D.&amp;rsquo;s that would obsess over details which did not matter in the grand scheme of things. You seem to have the ability to operate on multiple levels. Don&amp;rsquo;t lose the ability to see the bigger picture.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Now - The Role of Data in Adaptive Organizations</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2014-06-understanding-the-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 14:32:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2014-06-understanding-the-now/</guid>
      <description>It was 2005. The war in Iraq was raging. Many of us in the national security R&amp;amp;D community were developing responses to the deadliest threat facing US soldiers: the improvised explosive device (IED). From the perspective of the US military, the unthinkable was happening each and every day. The world’s most technologically advanced military was being dealt significant blows by insurgents making crude weapons from limited resources. How was this even possible?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Emergent Collaboration Through Community Sensemaking - Part 4</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-12-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 10:52:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-12-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-4/</guid>
      <description>The challenge of uncovering substantive collaborations stems from the fact that we are searching for clustering across relationship structure, social context and time. As we discussed in the previous post, our representational choices constrain the types of questions we can answer. By constructing a global interaction network, aggregating interaction activity across all locations in a Jive community, we conflated interactions occurring across a number of social contexts. This eliminated our ability to uncover clusters of interaction activity occurring in a particular social context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Emergent Collaboration Through Community Sensemaking - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-10-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 13:28:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-10-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-3/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, we discussed the core problem of identifying groups of users engaged in substantive collaboration and began to formulate a solution based on interaction graph analysis. At the end of the post, we examined the first global interaction graph I rendered for a large multinational corporation. While it was exciting to see this global view for the first time, the global interaction graph provides negligible practical insight without additional processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Emergent Collaboration Through Community Sensemaking - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-09-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 15:51:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-09-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I introduced a central question organizations ask after the deployment of a new social collaboration platform: &lt;em&gt;What business value is the platform delivering for our organization?&lt;/em&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to reflect on factors that affect the resulting business value. Without question, general usability will have a significant impact. If the savviest users cannot accomplish their work in a more efficient manner, the platform has little hope of offering additional value. Users must ultimately discover how best to map their work into the platform to realize efficiency gains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Emergent Collaboration Through Community Sensemaking - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-09-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 08:31:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-09-uncovering-emergent-collaboration-part-1/</guid>
      <description>As social media transformed communication in our personal lives, it was not long before companies began positioning themselves to bring a similar transformation to the enterprise. Fostering adoption of enterprise social media has not been easy, especially given prevailing beliefs among many that social media provides little practical benefit. Questions continue to linger in the early stages of deployment as organizations seek to understand the platform&amp;rsquo;s value proposition for their operational context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Beginning</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-08-a-new-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 10:59:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-08-a-new-beginning/</guid>
      <description>Friday, August 2nd marked my last official day as Jive&amp;rsquo;s principal data scientist. Over 2+ years there, working closely with Dave Gutelius, I gained a deeper perspective on enterprise social collaboration and ways in which new analytic capabilities could impact the adoption of social collaboration tools. Moving forward, the time has come to pursue some ideas that have been lingering on our minds for some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illuminating the Social Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-07-illuminating-the-social-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 12:32:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-07-illuminating-the-social-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Recently I participated in &lt;em&gt;The City Resilient&lt;/em&gt;, an event organized by PopTech and the Rockefeller Foundation to bring together individuals with diverse backgrounds and experience that share a common interest in advancing the resilience of our communities. Day one of the event consisted of presentations from leading innovators and scholars working on advancing and understanding various aspects of resilience, from the personal to the ecological scale. Day two engaged a smaller group of attendees in a design exercise to generate new concepts that might serve as meaningful responses to the challenges we heard the day prior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bias and Self-Interest: Timeless Constraints in the Era of Open Data</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-02-bias-and-self-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 08:46:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-02-bias-and-self-interest/</guid>
      <description>Senseless tragedies such as the recent Sandy Hook school shooting in Newtown, Connecticut give us pause as a nation and leave us struggling to understand how these acts happen all too often. With each loss, I begin to wonder if we are learning as a society. Are we truly reflecting on the problem or are we trapped in the same patterns that prevent us from moving forward? A closer look at how we respond hints at an answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber 2012: Crossing the Threshold</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-01-cyber-2012-crossing-the-threshold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 08:02:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2013-01-cyber-2012-crossing-the-threshold/</guid>
      <description>The evolution of the cyber domain is as fascinating as it is concerning. It is a perfect example of the complexity we constuct in our modern world that provides significant asymmetries in favor of those who choose to attack the system. In 2012, we witnessed the continued evolution of collection and attack capabilities to unprecedented levels. I thought it would be worthwhile to review some highlights from the past year that in my mind only bolster the case for strengthening community resilience before high consequence events occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grappling with Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-12-grappling-with-uncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 21:51:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-12-grappling-with-uncertainty/</guid>
      <description>This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to speak on several occasions with members of the national security community about organizational resilience in an uncertain world. These presentations have mainly been a continuation of musings that I began last year, leading me to write these two earlier posts on the subject. During these presentations, my aim has always been twofold: to make the audience more cognizant of the limits we face when attempting to reason about our world and to provide a general frame for thinking about operating in an environment that is fundamentally unpredictable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivating Challenges</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-11-motivating-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-11-motivating-challenges/</guid>
      <description>How might we inspire and enable communities to be inherently more resilient to global shocks and adaptive to changing realities?
Now, more than ever, it is imperative to search for viable answers to this question. In our globalized world, societies have become more fragile and vulnerable to cascading failures in networks. In domains such as cybersecurity, finance, energy production and distribution, the world continues to build systems whose complexities will never be fully understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Relationships for Social Good</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-05-building-relationships-for-social-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 20:54:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2012-05-building-relationships-for-social-good/</guid>
      <description>For some time now, I&amp;rsquo;ve firmly believed that the novel opportunities for innovation lie at the boundaries between disciplines. My word choice in this statement belies the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent many years up until recently in the research world. As I reflect on this now, I prefer the more general statement we obtain when replacing &lt;em&gt;disciplines&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;communities&lt;/em&gt;. New opportunities become apparent when ideas and resources that are constrained in separate communities are allowed to mix. Often their mixture is the catalyst for new perspective and, in some cases, new steps forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pursuing Meaningful Questions</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-11-pursuing-meaningful-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2011 13:10:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-11-pursuing-meaningful-questions/</guid>
      <description>Recently I read the description for the upcoming modeling challenge associated with the International Conference on Social Computing, Behavioral-Cultural Modeling, and Prediction. My initial reaction to the challenge can be summarized with one word: disappointment. I find this challenge emblematic of a significant body of research on social media that continues to pursue answers to questions that are misguided or poorly defined, leading to little practical benefit. Without the context of broader challenges, social media research will likely continue to generate results that fail to advance our understanding and deliver actionable insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Organizational Performance in an Uncertain World - Part 2 - Measure and React</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-08-optimizing-organizational-performance-in-an-uncertain-world-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 11:56:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-08-optimizing-organizational-performance-in-an-uncertain-world-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In a January 2011 report, the Economist Intelligence Unit published results from a survey of 300 senior executives from around the globe. The report highlighted a number of key challenges that businesses are grappling with as they face increasing complexity in the business environment. Global businesses serving diverse markets are expected to provide tailored products and more responsive customer service. Meeting these specialized needs while adapting to constraints within each marketplace has complicated decision-making. Meanwhile the timelines for comprehending the risks and making decisions have only grown shorter. How can organizations perform more effectively when faced with these challenges?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Organizational Performance in an Uncertain World - Part 1 - The Limits of Prediction</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-06-optimizing-organizational-performance-in-an-uncertain-world-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:04:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-06-optimizing-organizational-performance-in-an-uncertain-world-part-1/</guid>
      <description>How can technology enhance the performance of organizations? How does one characterize organizational performance in a world where our ability to predict is highly constrained? These are two general questions that have been on my mind for some time now. In an effort to clarify my thoughts on the matter and broaden the discussion, I thought I would summarize my view to date, providing the first of what I expect to be a series of blog posts on this general topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Complex, Dynamic Graph Data - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-04-exploring-complex-dynamic-graph-data-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 17:35:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-04-exploring-complex-dynamic-graph-data-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Since my last post, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reminded once again of the challenges presented by dynamic graph data. Earlier I wrote about how I&amp;rsquo;d hoped to exploit graph rewriting operations in Gremlin to efficiently tease out certain classes of communication event sequences in the Enron communication graph. Unfortunately the queries to produce those event sequences are nontrivial in Gremlin even with the abstraction provided through user-defined steps. At present, I think this is due to a mismatch between the representation I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen and the capabilities offered by Gremlin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Complex, Dynamic Graph Data - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-01-exploring-complex-dynamic-graph-data-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 19:00:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-01-exploring-complex-dynamic-graph-data-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In my first post, I advanced the idea that in order to conduct exploratory data analysis (EDA) we need four basic capabilities: persistence, query, analysis and visualization. Moving forward, I want to talk about specific approaches and capabilities I&amp;rsquo;ve examined that I believe provide value for EDA. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll focus on mechanisms for persistence and query.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve paid even the slightest attention to recent advances in the database world, it should be clear that the array of available capabilities is ever increasing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Your Attention Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-01-managing-your-attention-portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 15:29:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-01-managing-your-attention-portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Bradford Cross wrote a thought provoking blog post today on the idea of anti-personalization. I encourage you to read his post. In summary, he discusses the concern raised by some that personalization may have negative consequences on our perspective, by only serving to reinforce our current beliefs with additional content that is similar to what we&amp;rsquo;ve previously consumed. He then shares his initial thoughts on ways to potentially break that cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Complex, Dynamic Graph Data - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-01-exploring-complex-dynamic-graph-data-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 08:51:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2011-01-exploring-complex-dynamic-graph-data-part-1/</guid>
      <description>When I was in graduate school in the late 90s working on computer vision problems, MATLAB was my environment of choice. It provided all the tools I required for analysis and then some. Life was simple and grand.
Five years after leaving graduate school, I decided to take a dramatic turn in my research direction. Video surveillance no longer motivated me. Instead, I chose to explore problems at the interface between machine learning and the social sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categorizing Communication Mediums</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-09-categorizing-communication-mediums/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 15:24:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-09-categorizing-communication-mediums/</guid>
      <description>When thinking about social dynamics in online social systems, it is important to consider the attributes of the communication medium that bound the set of permissible interactions. This week I&amp;rsquo;ve been revisiting a set of dimensions along which to characterize communication mediums in general. Here is an expanded set based on past musings from several years ago and more recent discussions. I&amp;rsquo;m providing a working definition and a set of discrete values for each dimension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Signaling and Language Use</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-04-social-signaling-and-language-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 12:12:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-04-social-signaling-and-language-use/</guid>
      <description>Consider the following email from Tim Belden to John Lavorato and Louise Kitchen. Recall that Tim Belden was indicted for his role in conceiving and executing various financial schemes that allowed Enron to profit significantly from energy markets. Through the analysis of the Enron email collection, we would like to understand who Belden was reporting to and who he was supervising during the time period of the California energy crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Describing Twitter</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-04-describing-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 21:23:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-04-describing-twitter/</guid>
      <description>In the time since I&amp;rsquo;ve embraced Twitter and defined my personal use case for the platform, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of conversations with people who have asked for my perspective on Twitter. In some cases, the people I spoke with had limited experience with social media. In others, quite the opposite. At times it is difficult to know where to begin. Covering the defining characteristics of the platform is straightforward enough for those unaware. Clarifying the range of implications is far more challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking Relationships, Discovering Evidence</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-01-ranking-relationships-discovering-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2010 13:53:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2010-01-ranking-relationships-discovering-evidence/</guid>
      <description>In my introductory post on the topic of social relationship identification (SRI), I talked about the need to develop a collaborative process where the machine guides the analyst in the discovery of relevant social relationships and learns from the context provided by the analyst. Both the analyst and the machine have important and complementary roles to play in the analytic process. The question is what specific form should that collaborative process take?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interagency Collaboration: The Challenges Continue</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-interagency-collaboration-the-challenges-continue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 16:12:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-interagency-collaboration-the-challenges-continue/</guid>
      <description>Eight years after September 11th, it appears that very little has changed. With the latest attack, we return to the same discussion about the failure of our government to properly integrate bits of information distributed throughout different organizations to form a coherent view of an impending attack. In the course of that discussion, we state the obvious: we need to share. Yet we fail to address the challenges before us to make the obvious a reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Social Relationship: Issues of Representation</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-the-social-relationship-issues-of-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 14:13:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-the-social-relationship-issues-of-representation/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, the domain of social network analysis (SNA) has become very popular among research communities outside the traditional SNA community in sociology. From the perspective of the sociologists, this has been a mixed blessing. The discipline of SNA, having a strong computational basis, stands to benefit from additional perspectives from other fields. Yet far too often, to the dismay of the sociologists, there is a lack of recognition of the importance of representational choices made prior to analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Relationship Identification: Defining the Task</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-sri-defining-the-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 13:51:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-12-sri-defining-the-task/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, informal, online communication has transformed the way we connect and collaborate with others. Through a range of online communication technologies, we are able to enrich existing social relationships and establish new relationships that would otherwise be difficult or impossible to develop offline. Now that storage has become vast and inexpensive, much of this data will be archived for years to come. This provides new opportunities and new challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighborhood Networks</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-11-neighborhood-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 17:02:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2009-11-neighborhood-networks/</guid>
      <description>Not long after I moved into my new apartment, I experienced three separate power outages of significant duration within the span of 24 hours. Since my iPhone was charged and AT&amp;amp;T&amp;rsquo;s network remained operational, I was able to connect with the outside world and inquire about the situation. Given I now live in an area that is primed for earthquakes at any time, I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about how bad the situation could become if a significant event took place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weaving Trust Networks</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-12-weaving-trust-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2008 17:14:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-12-weaving-trust-networks/</guid>
      <description>Several years ago, I had the opportunity to listen to a retired Marine general who, upon leaving the military, continued to pursue his passion in the area of strategic collaboration. During the course of his military career, at various levels of command, he had seen and wrestled with the challenges of orchestrating the actions of multiple civilian and military organizations in dynamic, uncertain environments. During his presentation, his objective was to discuss the wicked hard problems in the extreme scenarios of disaster recovery and reconstruction events such as post-Hurricane Katrina operations and Iraq reconstruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honest Signals</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-11-honest-signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 15:16:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-11-honest-signals/</guid>
      <description>Each one of us has had the experience. We meet someone for the first time and immediately feel a resonance. We talk about how some people simply radiate, creating a presence that is hard to ignore. The nonverbal communication channel is powerful and shapes outcomes in social situations in profound ways. In recent years, Sandy Pentland&amp;rsquo;s research group at the MIT Media Lab has been systematically studying this communication pathway and characterizing more precisely the impact honest signals have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Phone Entrepreneurship in the Developing World</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-09-mobile-phone-entrepreneurship-in-the-developing-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 16:03:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-09-mobile-phone-entrepreneurship-in-the-developing-world/</guid>
      <description>This morning, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about an exciting ongoing project called EPROM (Entrepreneurial Programming and Research on Mobiles) that is focused on fostering mobile-phone related research and entrepreneurship in the developing world. The EPROM project is lead by Nathan Eagle, whose seminal Ph.D. research at the MIT Media Laboratory focused on understanding complex human dynamics from social interaction data derived from mobile devices.
To fully appreciate the motivation for EPROM, it is important to consider the trends within Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Citizens</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-09-empowering-citizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 03:07:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-09-empowering-citizens/</guid>
      <description>As Hurricane Gustav bears down on Louisiana, I can not help but think about the challenges of disaster response and how I believe we as a nation can do better. I believe communication technology, including social media, has an important role in this equation. Yet the most fundamental shift that is required is one of mindset.
Following September 11th, the push for homeland security has focused significantly on deploying technology to enhance the capabilities of security personnel and first responders to prevent or mitigate the impact of threats to the nation, whether natural or man-made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Transparency and Latent Group Discovery</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-08-social-transparency-and-latent-group-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2008 15:34:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-08-social-transparency-and-latent-group-discovery/</guid>
      <description>In March 2008, I participated in the AAAI Spring Symposium on Social Information Processing organized by Kristina Lerman (USC Information Sciences Institute), David Gutelius (Social Kinetics), Bernardo Huberman (HP Labs) and Srujana Merugu (Yahoo). The event brought together a very interesting mix of researchers investigating social media and the dynamic, emergent communities that are enabled by these technologies. Among the host of intriguing presentations, one in particular that caught my attention was given by Ed Chi from PARC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowdsourcing Cyberwar</title>
      <link>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-08-crowdsourcing-cyberwar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 02:47:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://research.navigating-the-edge.net/posts/2008-08-crowdsourcing-cyberwar/</guid>
      <description>On April 27, 2007, the Estonian government moved a controversial bronze statue of a Soviet soldier from its long-time resting place to a military graveyard outside the capital city of Tallinn. After 15 years of independence from the former Soviet Union, the government finally decided to take action to place this troubling symbol in a more remote location.  The reaction from the Russian minority was swift, with rioting and looting of downtown Tallinn that lasted for days.  Along with chaos in the streets came the beginning of a protracted cyberriot known now as the first Internet war.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
